<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>LLaMatters by Chirag Mehta</title>
    <link>https://llamatters.chir.ag/</link>
    <description>Recent content on LLaMatters by Chirag Mehta</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 05:55:27 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://llamatters.chir.ag/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Readability: Rewriting text to any comprehension level or length</title>
      <link>https://llamatters.chir.ag/posts/readability/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 05:55:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://llamatters.chir.ag/posts/readability/</guid>
      <description>Need for simplicity 🔗 Wikipedia is a great resource for getting a quick overview of a topic. But sometimes the articles are too long or too technical. Simple Wikipedia helps, although it can still be pretty lengthy and not always simple enough.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glossary: Acronyms, Definitions, Jargon</title>
      <link>https://llamatters.chir.ag/posts/glossary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2023 20:53:32 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://llamatters.chir.ag/posts/glossary/</guid>
      <description>Glossary 🔗 Keeping up with new lingo used in the field of Large Language Models (LLMs), itself a small subset of the ever-expanding world of AI/ML, is difficult, because every day new research papers coin new terms for novel algorithms or approaches.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://llamatters.chir.ag/posts/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2023 15:47:24 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://llamatters.chir.ag/posts/introduction/</guid>
      <description>LLaMatters 🔗ChatGPT &amp;amp; Beyond 🔗 As a user, ChatGPT is helpful. For many, it is an easy way to answer detailed questions or write essays and emails. But for those who wish to learn more, it can be a gateway into the world of large language models (LLMs), generative text, and context-aware responses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://llamatters.chir.ag/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2023 11:53:57 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://llamatters.chir.ag/about/</guid>
      <description>I am Chirag Mehta, programmer from Woodstock, IL. I started this blog to share my thoughts and experience learning about large language models and generative text.
You can contact me via this form.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
